Auto tool task number one, we have four class
diagram candidates.
And it says: “Which of these class diagram
candidates are valid class diagrams?”
We're going to use X modeler.
So, with X modeler, what should happen is
that if we managed to create one of these,
if we managed to create it, and it's exactly
the same, then it is a valid class diagram.
If X modeler interrupts and says there is
a problem, and it rejects it does not allow
us to create this class diagram and you have
these class diagrams, then it is invalid.
Let's do number one.
(10 sec) They have A, B, C, D, let's just
do them first and then we connect.
(6 sec) A is here, C is here and then B is
down here, D to the left.
Let's try to connect them.
So, they are connected now with inheritance.
No associations involved.
So, right click this, change parent to C.
So far, no problems.
Let me fix this.
Now, let's change parent of C make it B.
This is fine.
Let me fix this.
And now, parent of B should be D.
This is also fine.
And finally parent of D should be B. And it
says: “B is already a descendant of D, circular
inheritance is not allowed.”
So, this means this class diagram or actually
this class diagram candidate is not a class
diagram.
This is invalid.
Let's do the second one.
Let me remove this.
Actually, the second one also has A, B, C,
D. So, let me just add the class again.
Let me remove this.
It's not possible to remove this, I don't
think it's possible.
So, what I'm going to do is actually remove
them, yes.
And add B, add C. So, we have B here, we have
A in the middle and we have D here, we have
C here.
Change parent to B. Change parent to B change
parent to B. So, let me fix this mess.
(9 sec) And this looks exactly like the class
diagram here.
This means class diagram number 2 or candidate
number 2 is valid class diagram.
Now let's do number 3.
Change parent to B and fix this.
(16 sec) Change parent of B to D.
And change parent of D to A.
And change parent of A to B.
And again B is already a descendant of A,
circular inheritance is not allowed.
So, this means number three is also not a
class diagram.
This is invalid.
Let's do number four.
Change parent C. Change parent B, change parent
D. (19 sec) This should fix it.
And it looks exactly like this one.
So, this means number four is valid.
This is a class diagram in fact.